Applied and Decorative Arts Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- Illuminations (Manuscripts) (Box 7)
  - Carolingian (Box 8)
    - Reims School (Box 8)
      - Gospels of Hincmar (Reims, City Lib., Manuscripts7) (Box 8)
      - Loisel Gospels (Paris, Bib.Nat. Lat.17968) (Box 8)
    - Tours School (Box 8)
      - Various (Box 8)
      - Bamberg Bible (Box 8)
      - Evangelary (Paris, Bib.Nat.Lat.260) (Box 8)
      - Lothair Gospels [Slide box 48] (Box 8)
      - Moutier Grandval Bible (Box 8)
      - Vivian Bible (Box 8)
    - Metz School (Box 8)
      - Various (Box 8)
      - Sacramentary of Drogon (Box 8)
    - Charles the Bald Court School (Box 8)
      - San Paolo Bible (Box 8)
      - Charles the Bald Psalter (Paris, Lat.1152) (Box 8)
      - Sacramentary of Metz (Box 8)
      - S.Emmeram Gospels (Box 8)
    - Franco-Saxon School (Box 8)
      - Various (Box 8)
      - Francis II Gospel Book (Paris Lat.257) (Box 8)
      - Second Bible of Charles the Bald (Box 8)
    - St. Gall School (Box 8)
      - Book of Maccabees (Leiden, Univ.Lib.) (Box 8)
      - Golden Psalter (St. Gall manuscripts) [Slide boxes 48-49] (Box 8–9)
    - Fulda School [Slide box 49] (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
  - Austria (Box 9)
    - 12th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
      - Antiphonar of S. Peter (Vienna, cod.S.N.2700) (Box 9)
      - Bible from Admont(Vienna, coc. S.N.2701) (Box 9)
      - Liutold Gospels (Vienna, cod.1244) (Box 9)
    - 13th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
    - 14th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
    - 15th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
  - Armenia (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Britain (Box 9)
    - 10th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
      - Benedictional of S. Aethelwold (Box 9)
      - S.Severin Gospels (Morgan M.869) (Box 9)
    - 11th century [Slide box 50] (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
      - London (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
        - Aelfric's Pentateuch (Cotton Claudius B.1V) (Box 9)
        - Anglo-Saxon Calendar (Cotton Tiberius B.V) (Box 9)
        - Caligula Troper (Cotton Caligula A.XIV) (Box 9)
      - Oxford (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous [Slide box 51] (Box 9)
    - 12th century (Box 9)
      - Cambridge (Box 9)
        - Eadwine Psalter (Box 9)
        - Bury Bible (Box 9)
      - London (Box 9)
        - Westminster Abbey Psalter (Box 9)
        - Lambeth Bible [Slide 51-52] (Box 9)
      - New York (Box 9)
        - Lincoln Bestiary (Morgan M.81) (Box 9)
        - Life of S. Edmund (Morgan M.736) (Box 9)
        - Four Gospels (Morgan M.777) (Box 9)
      - Oxford (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous (all Bodleian manuscripts) (Box 9)
        - Marvels of the East (Bodley Manuscripts.614) (Box 9)
      - Winchester (Box 9)
        - Winchester Bible [Slide boxes 52-53] (Box 9)
    - 13th century (Box 9)
      - Various (Box 9)
      - Baltimore (Box 9)
        - Carrow Psalter (Walters manuscriptsW.34) (Box 9)
        - W.De Brailes: Scenes from a Bible (Walter manuscriptsW.106) (Box 9)
      - Belvoir Castle (Box 9)
        - Psalter c.1250 (Box 9)
      - Cambridge (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
        - Matthew Paris, Chronica Maiora (Corpus Christi manuscripts16) (Box 9)
        - Peterborough Psalter (Fitzwilliam Manuscripts12) (Box 9)
        - Trinity College Apocalypse (Box 9)
      - Dublin [Slide box 54] (Box 9)
      - Eton (Box 9)
        - Eton College Apocalypse (Box 9)
      - London (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 9)
        - Manuscript BM. ex Dyson Perrins lot 55 (Box 9)
        - Apocalypse BM ex Dyson Perrins lot 58 (Box 9)
        - Life of Becket leaves (BM Manuscripts88) (Box 9)
        - Life of S. Cuthbert(BM Add. Manuscripts39943) (Box 9)
        - Oscott Psalter (BM Add. Manuscripts 50000) (Box 9)
        - Harley Psalter (BM Harley Manuscripts 5102) (Box 9)
        - Psalter (BM Royal Manuscripts1.D x) (Box 9)
        - Psalter of Robert de Lindeseye (Soc.of Antiquaries) [Slide box 55] (Box 10)
      - Oxford (Box 10)
        - Various (Box 10)
        - Douce Apocalypse (Bodley ManuscriptsDouce 180) (Box 10)
        - English Bestiary (Bodley Manuscripts Ashmole 1511) (Box 10)
      - Paris (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
    - 14th century (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
      - Baltimore (Box 10)
        - Book of Hours (Walters Manuscripts W.105) (Box 10)
        - Psalter and Hours (Walters Manuscripts W.102) [Slide boxes 55-56] (Box 10)
      - Cambridge [Slide box 56] (Box 10)
        - Various (Box 10)
        - Book of Hours (Univ.Lib. manuscripts Dd.4.17) (Box 10)
        - Peterborough Psalter (Corpus Christi Manuscripts53) (Box 10)
      - London (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
        - Apocalypse (BM Royal 19.B.XV) (Box 10)
        - Liber Regalis (Westminster Abbey) (Box 10)
        - Psalter of Robert de Lisle (BM Arundel 83) (Box 10)
        - Queen Mary's Psalter (BM Royal Manuscripts 28.VII) (Box 10)
      - Malvern [Slide box 57] (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts coll. Dyson Perrins (Box 10)
      - New York (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts Morgan library (Box 10)
      - Oxford (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
        - Walter de Milemete, De Nobiltatibus…(Christ Church) (Box 10)
        - Infancy of Christ (Bodley manuscriptsSeld.Supra 39) (Box 10)
        - Ormesby Psalter (Bodley manuscriptsDouce 366) (Box 10)
    - 15th century (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
    - 16th century (Box 10)
      - Westminster Tournament Roll of 1511 (Box 10)
    - 19th-20th century (Box 10)
      - Various (William Morris and Burne-Jones) (Box 10)
  - Flanders (Box 10)
    - 11th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
      - Stavelot Bible (London BM Add. 28106-7 (Box 10)
    - 12th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
      - Averbode Gospels (Liege manuscripts 363.C) [Slide box 58] (Box 10)
      - London (Box 10)
        - Floreffe Bible (BM Add.ms 17737-8) (Box 10)
    - 13th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
    - 14th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
    - 15th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
      - Grimani Breviary (Box 10)
      - Baltimore (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts Walters Art Gallery (Box 10)
        - Book of Hours for the use of Arras (Walters manuscriptsW.166) (Box 10)
      - London (Box 10)
        - Various (Box 10)
        - Breviary of Isabella of Spain (BM Add. manuscripts18851) (Box 10)
        - Hours of Joanna the Mad (BM Add.ms 18852) (Box 10)
      - New Haven (Box 10)
        - L'arbre des Batallies (Beinecke 230) (Box 10)
        - Caesar, Commentaries (Beinecke 226) (Box 10)
        - Livy, Roman History (Phillipps ms 13332 now YUAG) (Box 10)
      - New York (Box 10)
        - Various (Box 10)
        - Hours of the Virgin c.1480 (Morgan M.6) (Box 10)
      - Oxford [Slide box 59] (Box 10)
        - Various (Box 10)
      - Turin (Box 10)
        - Van Eyck, Turin Hours (Box 10)
      - Vienna (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from the National Library (Box 10)
    - 16th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
      - Simon Bening, Prayer Book (Munich, Staatsbib.Clm.23638) (Box 10)
      - Joris Hoefnagel, Illus. to Mira Calligraphiae Monumenta (Getty Mus.) (Box 10)
      - New York (Box 10)
        - Breviary for Queen Eleanor of Portugal (Morgan M.52) (Box 10)
        - Hours of the Virgin c.1515 (Morgan M. 399) (Box 10)
  - France (Box 10)
    - 9th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
    - 10th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
    - 11th century [Slide box 60] (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
      - Paris (Box 10)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 10)
        - Apocalypse of S. Sever (Bib.Nat.Lat.8878) (Box 10)
        - 2d Bible of S. Martial (Bib.Nat. Lat.8) (Box 10)
        - Life of S. Aubin (Bib.Nat. Nouv.Acq.Lat.1390) (Box 10)
        - Psalter, S. Germain-des-Pres (Bib.Nat. Lat.11550) (Box 10)
        - Troper-Proser from Auch (Bib.Nat.lat.1118) (Box 10)
    - 12th century (Box 10)
      - Various (Box 10)
      - Harrad of Hohenburg, Hortus Deliciarum (facsimile) (Box 10)
      - Lambert of S. Omer, Liber Floridus (Wolfenguttel copy) [Slide box 61] (Box 11)
      - Avanches (Box 11)
        - Cartulary of Mont S. Michel (Box 11)
      - Baltimore (Box 11)
        - Gospel book (Walters W.17) (Box 11)
      - Dijon (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - Douai (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - Moulins (Box 11)
        - Souvigny Bible (Box 11)
      - Paris (Box 11)
        - Various (Box 11)
        - Bib.Nat. miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
          - Sacramentary of S.Etienne of Limoges (Lat.9438) (Box 11)
      - Parma (Box 11)
        - Parma Ildefonsus (Box 11)
      - Troyes (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
    - 13th century (Box 11)
      - Various (Box 11)
        - Baltimore (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
        - Chantilly (Box 11)
          - Psalter of Ingeborg (Box 11)
        - London (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
        - New Haven [Slide box 62] (Box 11)
          - Beinecke and Medical Library manuscripts (Box 11)
        - New York (Box 11)
          - Hours of the Virgin (Morgan M.92) (Box 11)
          - Old Testament Illustrations (Morgan M.638) (Box 11)
          - Psalter and Hours of the Virgin (Morgan M.729) (Box 11)
        - Paris (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
          - Bible Moralisee (Bib.Nat.Lat.11560) (Box 11)
          - Breviary of Philippe le Bell (Bib.Nat.Lat.1023) (Box 11)
          - Credo of Joinville (Bib.Nat. Lat.11907) (Box 11)
          - Evangelary of S.Chapelle (Bib.Nat. Lat.8892) (Box 11)
          - Frederick II Treatise on Falconry (Bib.Nat. Fr.12.400) (Box 11)
          - Grandes Chroniques de France (Bib.Genevieve 782) (Box 11)
          - Psalter of S.Louis (Bib.Nat. Lat.10525) (Box 11)
        - Troyes [Slide box 63] (Box 11)
          - Various (Box 11)
        - Vienna (Box 11)
          - Bible Moralisee (Nat.Lib. Manuscripts2554) (Box 11)
    - 14th century (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - Baltimore (Box 11)
        - Missal for the use of Paris (Walters W.124) (Box 11)
      - Escorial (Box 11)
        - Matfre Ermengau, Breviari d'Amor (Box 11)
      - The Hague (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - London (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
        - Coronation Book of Charles V (Box 11)
        - Roman de la Rose (BM various manuscripts) (Box 11)
        - Roman de la Rose (BM Add.31840) (Box 11)
      - New York (Box 11)
        - Cloisters Apocalypse (Box 11)
        - Jean Pucelle, Hours of Jeanne d'Evreux [Slide box 64] (Box 11)
      - Oxford (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - Paris (Box 11)
        - Various (Box 11)
        - Bib.Nat. miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
          - Grandes Chroniques de France (Fr.2613) (Box 11)
          - Guillaume de Machaut (Fr.1586) (Box 11)
          - Life of S.Denis (Fr.2090-2092) (Box 11)
          - Jean LeNoir, Breviary of Charles V [Slide box 65] (Box 11)
          - Jean LeNoir, Hours of Jeanne de Navarre (Box 11)
          - Petite Heures de Duc de Berry (Box 11)
          - Psalter of Jean de Berry (Box 11)
          - Jean Pucelle, Belleville Breviary (Box 11)
          - Roman de la Rose (various manuscripts) (Box 11)
          - Roman de la Rose (Fr.1563) (Box 11)
          - Tres Belles Heures du Duc de Berry (Box 11)
    - 15th century (including works or collections in Aix-en-Provence, Arras, Cleveland, Dresden, Lyon, Macau, and Weingarten) (Box 11)
      - Baltimore (Box 11)
        - Walters miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
        - Breviary for Rome (W.300) (Box 11)
        - Book of Hours (W.231) (Box 11)
        - Book of Hours (W.265) [Slide box 65-66] (Box 11)
      - Brussels [Slide box 66] (Box 11)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 11)
      - Chantilly (Box 11)
        - Jean Fouquet, Hours of Etienne Chevalier (Box 11)
        - Pol de Limbourg, Tres Riches Leures de Duc de Berry [Slide boxes 66-67] (Box 11–12)
      - London [Slide box 67] (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
        - Roman de la Rose, (BM Egerton2022) (Box 12)
      - New Haven (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
        - S.Augustine, City of God (Beinecke 215) (Box 12)
      - New York (Box 12)
        - Morgan Library miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
        - Jean Colombe, Hours of the Virgin (M.677) (Box 12)
        - Hours of the Virgin (M.834) (Box 12)
        - Limbourg Brothers, Belles Heures du Jean de Berry (Cloisters) (Box 12)
        - Bedford Master, Hours of the Virgin (M.453) [Slide box 68] (Box 12)
      - Oxford (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
        - Roman de la Rose (Bodley Douce 195 and 341) (Box 12)
      - Paris (Box 12)
        - Boucicaut Hours (Box 12)
        - Bib.Nat. miscellaneous manuscripts [Slide boxes 68-69] (Box 12)
          - Antiquites Judaiques (Fr.247) [Slide box 69] (Box 12)
          - Boucicaut Master, Livre des Merveilles (Fr.2810) (Box 12)
          - Bible Moralisee (Fr.166) (Box 12)
          - Book of Hours of Louis of Savoie (Lat.9473) (Box 12)
          - Breviary of the Duke of Bedford (Lat.17294) (Box 12)
          - Cite des Dames (Fr.607) (Box 12)
          - Boccaccio, Des Cleres et Nobles Femmes (Fr.599) (Box 12)
          - Jean Fouquet, Grandes Chroniques de France (Fr.6465) (Box 12)
          - Jean Fouquet, Tite-livre (Fr.20071) (Box 12)
          - Gaston Phebus, Livre de la Chasse (Lat.616) (Box 12)
          - Grandes Heures du Duc de Berry (Lat.919) (Box 12)
          - Grandes Heures de Rohan (Lat.9471) (Box 12)
          - Livre des Tournois (Fr.2692) (Box 12)
          - Roman de la Rose (Fr.R.24392) (Box 12)
      - Vienna (Box 12)
        - Various (Box 12)
        - Livre du Coeur d'Amor Epris de Rene d'Anjou (Cod.Vind.2597) (Box 12)
    - 16th century [Slide box 70] (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
      - Baltimore (Box 12)
        - Various (Box 12)
      - New York (Box 12)
        - Jean Bourdichon, Hours of the Virgin (M.732) (Box 12)
        - Jean Bourdichon, Lallemant Missal (M.495) (Box 12)
        - Jean Bourdichon, Prayerbook of Marechal de Gie (M.292) (Box 12)
        - Hours of the Virgin (M.632) (Box 12)
      - Paris (Box 12)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
        - Jean Bourdichon, Grandes Heures of Anne of Brittany (Box 12)
    - 17th century (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
  - Germany (Box 12)
    - 10th century (Box 12)
      - Various (Box 12)
      - Codex Egberti (Box 12)
      - Evangelary of Otto III [Slide box 71] (Box 12)
      - Gero Codex (Box 12)
      - Otto and 4 parts of empire, Chantilly fragment (Box 12)
      - S.Gregory and Decon Paul, Trier fragments (Box 12)
    - 11th century (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 12)
      - Bamberg Apocalypse (Box 12)
      - Evangelary of Fulda [Slide box 72] (Box 12)
      - Golden Gospels of Echternach (Box 12)
      - Gospel Book, Reichenau school (Baltimore, Walters W.7) (Box 12)
      - Gospels of Henry III (Escorial Vitr.17) (Box 12)
      - Gospels of Otto III (Munich Lat.4453) (Box 12)
      - Limburg Evangelary (Cologne) (Box 12)
      - Pericopes of Henry II (Munich Lat.4452) (Box 12)
      - Sacramentary of Henry II (Munich Clm.4456) (Box 12)
    - 12th century (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts [Slide boxes 72-73] (Box 12–13)
      - Gospels of Henry the Lion [Slide box 73] (Box 13)
      - Hidegard von Bingen, Scivias (Wiesbaden) (Box 13)
      - Isidore of Seville, Etymologiae (Munich and Stuttgart ms) (Box 13)
      - Speculum Virginum (Baltimore Walters W.72) (Box 13)
    - 13th century (Box 13)
      including works or collections in Heidelberg, Munich, New York City, Stuttgart, Wiesbaden, Wolfenbuttel
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
      - Scheyern Matutinal (Box 13)
      - Berthold Missal (Morgan M.710) (Box 13)
      - Breviary from Hildesheim [Slide box 74] (Box 13)
      - Devil's Bible, Bohemia (Stockholm A.148) (Box 13)
      - Heinrich von Veldeke, Eneide (Berlin manuscriptsF.282) (Box 13)
    - 14th century (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
      - Bible of Wenceslas (Vienna Cod.2759) (Box 13)
    - 15th century (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
    - 16th century (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
  - Holland (Box 13)
    - Various (Box 13)
    - Hours of Catherine of Cleves (Morgan Library) [Slide boxes 74-75] (Box 13)
    - Missal from Utrecht c.1430 (Baltimore, Walters W.174) [Slide box 75] (Box 13)
    - Spiegel van den Leven und Heren (Morgan M.868) (Box 13)
  - Italy (Box 13)
    - 9th-10th centuries (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
    - 11th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
      - Montecassino: Rabanus Maurus Encyclopedia (Box 13)
      - Paris (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
      - Rome (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous Vatican manuscripts (Box 13)
    - 12th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
      - Pantheon Bible (Vatican Lat.12958) (Box 13)
    - 13th century (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
    - 14th century [Slide box 76] (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
      - Florence (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Laurenziana and others (Box 13)
      - Forli (Box 13)
        - Officium manuscripts853 (Box 13)
      - Milan (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Ambrosiana and others (Box 13)
      - New Haven (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from YUAG and Beinecke (Box 13)
      - New York (Box 13)
        - Florentine Choir Book (Morgan M.653) (Box 13)
      - Padua (Box 13)
        - Gerardino, Antiphonary, 1306 (Cathedral) (Box 13)
      - Paris (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Bib.Nat. (Box 13)
      - Rome (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from S.Croce, S.Spirito, Vatican (Box 13)
    - 15th century (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Siena, Albi, Oxford, Bologna and others [slide boxes 76-77] (Box 13)
    - Florence [Slide box 77] (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Laurenziana, Riccardiana, Duomo (Box 13)
      - London (Box 13)
        - Brooke Antiphonal (Box 13)
        - Giovanni di Paolo, Dante, Paradiso (Box 13)
        - Giuliamo Amadei, Pliny, Natural History (Box 13)
        - Plutarch, Lives (BM Add.22318) (Box 13)
      - New Haven (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from Beinecke Library (Box 13)
      - New York (Box 13)
        - Misceelaneous manuscripts (Box 13)
        - Medici Aesop (NYPL Spencer Manuscripts50) (Box 13)
      - Paris (Box 13)
        - Miscelaneous manuscripts from Bib.Nat. (Box 13)
        - Speculum Humanae Salvationis (Bib.Nat.lat.9584) (Box 13)
      - Rome [Slide box 78] (Box 13)
        - Miscellaneous manuscripts from the Vatican (Box 13)
      - Venice (Box 13)
        - Biblia Pauperum (Marciana Lat.72) (Box 13)
    - 16th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
    - 17th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
    - 18th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
  - Portugal (Box 13)
    - Various (Box 13)
  - Spain (Box 13)
    - Various (Box 13)
    - 10th century (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
      - Beatus (Escorial manuscripts11.5) (Box 13)
      - Beatus (Gerona Cathedral manuscripts7) (Box 13)
      - Beatus (Morgan M.644) [Slide box 78-79] (Box 13–14)
      - Beatus (Seo de Urgell) [Slide box 79] (Box 14)
      - Beatus (Valladolid) (Box 14)
      - Bible of 920 (Leon) (Box 14)
      - Bible of 960 (Leon) (Box 14)
      - Codex Vigilanus (Escorial) (Box 14)
      - Gregory, Moralia in Job (Madrid Cod.80) (Box 14)
      - Silos Offices (BM Add.30.844) (Box 14)
      - Silos Sanctoral (BM Add.30.845) (Box 14)
    - 11th century (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
      - Antiphonal of Silos (BM Add. 30.850) (Box 14)
      - Beatus (Burgo de Osma) (Box 14)
      - Beatus (Madrid Vit.14-2) (Box 14)
      - Bible of Roda (Paris Bib.Nat.Lat.6) (Box 14)
    - 12th century (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
      - Beatus (BM Add.11695) (Box 14)
      - Beatus (BM Add.11696) (Box 14)
      - Beatus (Cloisters) (Box 14)
      - Codex Calixtinus (Santiago da Compostela) (Box 14)
    - 13th century (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
      - Beatus (Morgan M.429) (Box 14)
      - Las Cantias de S.Maria (Escorial manuscriptsB.I.2) [Slide boxes 78-79] (Box 14)
    - 14th century [Slide box 80] (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
    - 15th century (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
    - 16th century (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
  - Latin America (Box 14)
    - Ecuador (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
    - Mexico (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
- Industrial Design (Box 14)
  - Appliances (Box 14)
  - Bathroom Fixtures [Slide box 81] (Box 14)
  - Calculators, Computers (Box 14)
  - Cameras (Box 14)
  - Clocks and Watches (Box 14)
  - Lighting Fixtures (Box 14)
    - Bauhaus Design Lamps (Box 14)
    - Lamps by Donald Deskey (Box 14)
    - Lamps by Frank Gehry (Box 14)
  - Locks (Box 14)
  - Machines (Box 14)
  - Measuring and Testing (Box 14)
  - Microscopes (Box 14)
  - Radios [Slide box 82] (Box 14)
  - Record Players (Box 14)
  - Refrigerators, Stoves, etc. (Box 14)
  - Sewing Machines (Box 14)
  - Telephones (Box 14)
  - Tools (Box 14)
  - Toys (Box 14)
  - Typewriters (Box 14)
- Intarsia (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 14)
  - Roman (Box 14)
    - Ostia (Box 14)
      - Building outside Porta Marina (Box 14)
      - House of Armor & Psyche (Box 14)
    - Rome (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous works [Slide boxes 82-83] (Box 14)
- Ivory (Box 14)
  [Slide box 83]
  - Miscellaneous Near East (Box 14)
  - Early Medieval (Box 14)
  - 4th century (Box 14)
    - Milan Diptych (Box 14)
  - 5th century (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Circus Scenes Diptych (Box 14)
    - Procession carrying relics (Box 14)
    - Quirinian (Box 14)
  - 6th century [Slide boxes 83-84] (Box 14)
    - Aeobindus Diptych [Slide box 84] (Box 14)
    - Barbarini (Box 14)
    - Daniel (Box 14)
    - Standing Empress (Box 14)
  - 7th century (Box 14)
  - 9th century (Box 14)
  - 10th century (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Adam & Eve Caskets (Box 14)
    - Caskets Fragments (Box 14)
    - Christ crowning (Box 14)
    - Evangelary cover [Slide boxes 84-85] (Box 14–15)
  - 11th century [Slide box 85] (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Veroli Casket (Box 15)
  - 12th century (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Vatican Triptych (Box 15)
    - Caskets, Berlin (Box 15)
    - Caskets, NY Metropolitan (Box 15)
    - Melisende Psalter cover (Box 15)
    - Triptych of 40 Martyrs (Box 15)
  - Barbarian (Box 15)
  - Anglo-Saxon (Box 15)
  - Carolingian (Box 15)
  - Britain [Slide box 86] (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Bury St. Edmund's Cross (Box 15)
  - France (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Germany (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Italy (Box 15)
  - Spain (Box 15)
- Jewelry (Box 15)
  [Slide box 87]
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Anglo-saxon (Box 15)
  - Early Medieval – Byzantine (Box 15)
  - Austria (Box 15)
  - Britain (Box 15)
  - France (Box 15)
  - Germany (Box 15)
  - Spain (Box 15)
  - United States (Box 15)
- Maps (Box 15)
  [Slide box 88]
  - General (Box 15)
    This section includes all-purpose maps from current atlases
    - World (Box 15)
    - Africa (Box 15)
    - Asia (Box 15)
      - China (Box 15)
      - Japan (Box 15)
      - India (Box 15)
    - Europe (Box 15)
      - Britain (Box 15)